Guide to the Keith-McHenry-Pond Family Papers, 1841-1961
The Bancroft Library.
- Journals, Scrapbooks and Guestbooks
  - Scrapbook of clippings re William Keith, 1902-1903 (Carton 13)
  - Three Scrapbooks of clippings re music
  - Guest Registers, Keith Art Association, 1945-1953 (2)
  - Business Cards and Calling Cards
    Arranged alphabetically in two boxes
- Clippings
  - Arranged as follows: (Carton 14)
    - Obituaries
    - William Keith, Keith Art Association, etc.
    - Streets of San Francisco and Berkeley
    - Missions
    - Mary (McHenry) Keith, John McHenry
    - Woman Suffrage
    - Music
    - World Wars I II
    - Pond Family, Navy, Ships, etc.
    - Miscellany
  - Card files (4" x 6"), compiled by E. K. Pond.
    Annotated bibliography of works (books, articles, exhibitions, etc.) by or about William Keith, ca. 1856-1950. Arranged chronologically. 2 boxes
  - Card files containing excerpts and summaries of letters in the Keith Miscellanea.
    Arranged alphabetically by name of writer. 1 box
- Oversize Materials
  - William Keith (Oversize Folder 1 B)
    - Certificate of Gold Medal, Alaska-Yukon-Pacific Exposition, 1909
    - Certificate of Silver Medal, Massachusetts Charitable Mechanic Association, 1878
  - Mary (McHenry) Keith
    - Diploma, San Francisco Girls' High School, 1875 (Oversize Folder 1 B)
    - Certificate of Admission to the Bar, California State Supreme Court, 1882 (Oversize Folder 1 B)
    - Honor Roll, National American Woman Suffrage Association, 1920. Signed by Carrie Chapman Catt (Oversize Folder 1 B)
    - Poster and Sheet Music (item removed and catalogued separately) re Woman Suffrage (Oversize Folder 1 B)
    - Bachelor of Arts Degree, University of California, 1879. (Oversize Folder 1 B)
    - Bachelor of Law Degree, Hastings College of Law, 1882. Removed to the University Archives (Oversize Folder 1 B)
    - Woman Suffrage posters, n.d. (Oversize Folder 1 B)
    - Votes for Women banner, n.d. (Oversize Folder 2 A)
  - Elizabeth Keith Pond (Oversize Folder 1 B)
    - Membership Certificate, United Daughters of the Confederacy, n.d.
  - Emma (McHenry) Pond (Oversize Folder 1 B)
    - Membership Certificate, United Daughters of the Confederacy, n.d.
    - Membership Certificate, Daughters of the American Revolution, 1913
    - Certificate as Chapter Regent, Daughters of the American Revolution, 1913
  - Charles Fremont Pond (Oversize Folder 1 B)
    - Domain of Neptunus Rex, 1909
  - Mary Emma Zuleika (Metcalfe) Hay (Oversize Folder 1 B)
    - Diploma, Worcester High School, 1861
Partial List of Correspondents
- Adams, Ansel Easton, 1902-
  - Letter, [1929], to Elizabeth Keith Pond, re her father's death. (Carton 5)
- Aiken, Ednah (Robinson), 1872-1960
  - 2 letters, 1925-1926, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Re authentication of several of her Keith paintings. (Box 5)
- American Association of University Women. San Francisco Bay Branch
  - 4 letters, 1927-1947, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Inviting her to attend their anniversary meetings. (Box 5)
- American Fine Arts Association
  - Letter, Nov. 20, 1906, to William Keith. Written by R. A. Bernstein, President and Manager. Requesting that he be allowed to handle Keith's next exhibition. (Box 2)
- Amundsen, Jane
  - 27 letters, 1937-1947 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Some letters written while Director of Art Exhibition, Golden Gate International Exposition. (Box 5)
  - Letter, Sept. 19, 1940, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Written while Director of Art Exhibition, Golden Gate International Exposition. (Carton 5)
- Anthony, Susan Brownell, 1820-1906 See also: letter, Sept. 1, 1896, in scrapbook of clippings re woman suffrage, 1896, in Ctn. 4.
  - 11 letters, 1896-1905, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 5)
  - Letter, Mar. 10, 1903, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. (Box 15)
- Atlantic Publishing and Engraving Co.
  - 2 letters, 1880-1881, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. Written by A.C. Rogers, President. Re printing her book The Wandering Jew. (Box 15)
- Avery, Rachel G. (Foster), 1858-1919 See also: Catt, Carrie Chapman National American Woman Suffrage Association
  - 5 letters, 1900-1907, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written for the National American Woman Suffrage Association mainly re establishing a fund as a memorial to S. B. Anthony. With these: draft of appeal for funds. (Box 5)
- Bad, William Frederic, 1871-1936
  - 2 letters, 1920-1922, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Thanking her for sending John Muir letters to William Keith for him to copy. (Box 5)
  - Letter, Mar. 31, 1931, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
- Baeck, Anna Wooster (Rearden), 1888-1970
  - 2 letters, 1937 n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 5)
  - 2 letters, 1942-1945, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
- Balentine, Katharine Reed
  - 2 letters, 1906-1907, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Letter, 1906, written while editor, The Yellow Ribbon, a newspaper she started which was devoted to woman's suffrage on the Pacific Coast. Letter, 1907, written while Recording Secretary, Equal Suffrage League of San Francisco. (Box 5)
- Bancroft, Eleanor (Ashby), 1903-1956 See Bancroft Library
- Bancroft (A. L.) Company
  - 4 letters, 1878-1881, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. Re publishing and selling her book. (Box 15)
- Bancroft Library
  - 22 letters, 1939-1954, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Written by H. I. Priestley, E. Bancroft, G. P. Hammond others. Primarily acknowledging gifts to the Library. Letter, Nov. 22, 1944, written by M. E. Deutsch, Chairman and R. L. Underhill, Secretary, Committee on the Herbert I. Priestley Fund. (Carton 5)
- Bard, Thomas Robert, 1841-1915
  - 2 letters, 1902, to Charles Fremont Pond. Written while U.S. Senator from California. Re Pond's request to secure an appointment to West Point for his son, Charles McHenry Pond. Letter, Oct. 15, written for him by his secretary. (Carton 6)
- Barkle, Thomas J.
  - 8 letters, 1939-1942, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Re obtaining Keith items for his museum in Monterey, Calif. (Box 5)
- Barrus, Clara, 1864-1931
  - 3 letters, 1909-1910, to William Keith. (Box 2)
- Bates, George
  - 2 letters, 1886-1887, to Emmanuel Benjamin Lamare. Letters of recommendation for position of French instructor at the University of California, Berkeley. (Box 19)
- Bechtel, Kenneth Karl, 1904-1978
  - Letter, June 1, 1943, to Brother Cornelius. Copy, written while President, Marinship Corporation. Re naming a ship for William Keith. (Carton 9)
- Belmont, Calif. College of Notre Dame. Alumnae Association
  - 2 letters, 1931, to Mary Emma Zuleika (Metcalfe) Hay. Asking her to write an article about her experiences at Notre Dame. Copies. (Box 21)
- Bender, Albert Maurice, 1866-1941
  - Letter, Apr. 18, 1932, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written for him by W. J. Dawson. (Box 5)
- Berkeley, Calif. Chamber of Commerce
  - 2 letters, 1911-1912, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written by Wells Drury. Letter, 1912, asks her to consider having a Keith exhibition in Berkeley. (Box 5)
- Berkeley, Calif. Public Library
  - 5 letters, 1935-1936, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written by S. T. Smith, Librarian. Letter, Oct. 26, 1936, concerns a Keith painting presented to the Library. Letter, 1935, is a copy. (Box 5)
- Berkeley (Calif.) Humane Society
  - 2 letters, 1928, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 5)
- Blackwell, Alice Stone, 1857-1950
  - 5 letters, 1908-1914, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Postcard, [Dec. 30, 1909], written to A. L. Park.
- Blake, Anita Day (Symmes), 1872-1962 [Mrs. Anson Stiles Blake]
  - Letter, Oct. 15, 1947, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
- Blake, Anson Stiles, 1870-1959
  - 2 letters, 1947, to Keith Art Association. (Carton 9)
- Blanding, Gordon, 1849-1945
  - Letter, Apr. 6, 1909, to William Keith. Thanking him for his gift of a painting of Hetch Hetchy. (Box 2)
  - 2 letters, 1941, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Letter, Aug. 5, concerns his Keith painting "Native Sons." Letter, Apr. 15, written for him by his secretary. (Box 5)
- Bliss, Leslie Edgar, 1890-1977 See Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery
- Bok, Edward William, 1863-1930
  - Letter, n.d., to William Keith. 3 pen and ink sketches on the back of the letter. (Box 2)
- Borland, Sarah C.
  - 5 letters, 1911 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written mainly while corresponding secretary, California Equal Suffrage Association. Letter, Apr. 17, written while corresponding secretary, Equal Suffrage Amendment League of Oakland. Several letters written to Mrs. A. McBean. (Box 5)
- Boston, Mass. Public Library
  - Letter, Sept. 16, 1933, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Written by M. E. Lord, Director. Transmits list of articles about Keith in Boston newspapers, 1872. (Carton 5)
- Brackenbury, Georgina Agnes, d. 1949
  - 6 letters, 1899 and n.d., to William Keith. (Box 2)
  - 3 letters, 1940 and n.d. Letter, n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith; letters, 1940, are copies addressed to her brother. With these: excerpt (copy) from a letter re a robot bomb which hit near their London home. (Box 5)
- Brackenbury, Marie V. C.
  - 18 letters, 1899-1911 and n.d., to William Keith. (Box 2)
  - 23 letters, 1911-1941, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Letter (copy), Sept. 21, 1940, is addressed to her brother. With these: New Year card, n.d. (Box 5)
  - 5 letters, 1931-1932 and n.d., to Elizabeth Keith Pond. One letter, n.d., is incomplete. (Carton 5)
  - 3 letters (copies), 1940-1943 and n.d., to Brother Cornelius. Letter, 1943, written in part by her sister, Georgina. (Carton 9)
- Brackenbury, Richard
  - 2 letters, 1898-1899, to William Keith. Re helping to sell Keith paintings in London and Denver. (Box 2)
  - 6 letters, 1940-1945, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Letter, Feb. 18, 1945, transmits printed copies of several of his poems. (Box 5)
  - 3 letters, 1945-1946 n.d., to Brother Cornelius. (Carton 9)
- Bradford, Royal Bird, 1844-
  - Letter, Mar. 30, 1900, to Charles Fremont Pond. Re survey of the Midway Islands. (Carton 6)
- Braly, John Hyde
  - 3 letters, 1912-1920, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 5)
- Bray, Absalom Francis, 1889-
  - Letter, Feb. 18, 1941, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 5)
- Bridgman, Lilian, d. 1948
  - 5 letters, 189[?]-1943 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Letter, Dec. 17, 1943, is a copy. (Box 5)
  - Letter, Feb. 24, 1945, to Keith Art Association. (Carton 9)
- Brown, A. Page, 1859-1896
  - Letter, May 31, 1892, to William Keith. (Box 2)
- Brownson, Willard Herbert, 1845- See U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey
- Bruce, George T., 1857-1942 [William Keith's cousin]
  - 22 letters, 1939-1942, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Letter, Jan. 14, 1940, written to E. K. Pond. (Box 5)
- Burnett, Peter Hardeman, 1807-1895
  - Letter, July 21, 1881, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. (Box 15)
- Burnham, Daniel Hudson, 1846-1912
  - 4 letters, 1907-1910, to William Keith. (Box 2)
  - 3 letters, 1885-1911, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 5)
- Burnham, Margaret S. [Mrs. Daniel Hudson Burnham]
  - 5 letters, 1911-1945, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. With these: 4 greeting cards, n.d. (Box 5)
  - Letter, Mar. 24, 1931, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
- California. Governor
  - 2 letters, 1952, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Written for Earl Warren by his Private Secretary. Re Keith's painting "Springtime in San Rafael" which was hung in the office. (Carton 5)
  - Letter (copy), May 11, 1943, to Brother Cornelius. Written by Earl Warren. Thanking him for sending a copy of his Keith biography. (Carton 9)
- California. State Library, Sacramento
  - 2 letters, 1932, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Written by M. R. Gillis, State Librarian. Requesting material for their California authors file. (Carton 5)
- California. University. College of Agriculture
  - 5 letters, 1889, to Charles Fremont Pond. Written by E. L. Greene. Relate mainly to specimens Pond sent for their collections. (Carton 6)
- California. University. Comptroller
  - Letter (copy), Aug. 20, 1928, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written by R. G. Sproul. Re sale of a lot to the University of California. (Box 6)
- California. University. President See also: Wheeler, Benjamin Ide
  - 2 letters, 1939-1943, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Written by R. G. Sproul. Letter, 1943, written for him by M. E. Deutsch. (Carton 5)
  - Letter, May 5, 1945, to Brother Cornelius. Written by R. G. Sproul. (Carton 9)
  - Letter, May 9, 1944, to R. L. Underhill. Written by R. G. Sproul. Re securing funds for a memorial to Professor H. I. Priestley. In Miscellaneous Correspondence (Carton 9)
- California. University. Regents
  - 7 letters, 1930-1942, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Written mainly by R. M. Underhill, Secretary and Treasurer. (Carton 5)
- California. University, Berkeley. Library
  - 3 letters, 1932, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Written by J. C. Rowell, Librarian Emeritus. Thanking her for giving copies of her books to the Library. (Carton 5)
- California. University, Berkeley. Museum of Vertebrate Zoology
  - Letter, Feb. 11, 1924, to Charles Fremont Pond. Written by Joseph Grinnell, Director. Acknowledging Pond's gift to the Museum of a bird specimen. (Carton 6)
- California Anti-Rodeo-Cruelty Association
  - Letter, Apr. 17, 1928, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written by S. E. Manchester, thanking her for her support. (Box 6)
- California Equal Suffrage Association See also: Borland, Sarah C. Schlingheyde, Clara M. Taylor, Lucretia (Watson) Watson, Elizabeth (Lowe)
  - 20 letters, 1906-1911 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written by Mary T. Gamage, Helen Moore, Mary S. Sperry and others. One letter, n.d., is form letter written by Mrs. Keith soliciting funds for the Susan B. Anthony Memorial Fund. (Box 6)
- California Historical Society
  - 2 letters, 1956, to Inez (Henderson) Pond. Thanking her for her gift of Keith and Pond family papers and photographs. (Carton 7)
- California League of Women Voters
  - Letter, May 10, 1938, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written by Janet (Choynski) Fleishhacker. (Box 6)
- California Palace of the Legion of Honor
  - 3 letters, 1932, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written by T. C. Howe, Assistant Director, re borrowing a Keith painting. (Box 6)
- California Woman Suffrage Association See Schlingheyde, Clara M.
- Calkins, Wolcott, 1831-
  - 2 letters, 1917 and n.d., to Mary Emma Zuleika (Metcalfe) Hay. (Box 21)
- Campaign For World Government
  - Letter, May 2, 1945, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written by Georgia Lloyd, Director. (Box 6)
- Catt, Carrie Chapman, 1859-1947 See also: Avery, Rachel G. (Foster) National American Woman Suffrage Association
  - 4 letters, 1900-1937, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Letters, 1900-1922, written while President, National American Woman Suffrage Association. Letter (copy), Feb. 16, 1920, notifies Mrs. Keith that she has been placed on the Honor Roll for distinguished service to woman suffrage in America. (Box 6)
  - Letter, May 1, 1945, to Brother Cornelius. (Carton 9)
- Chamberlain, Anna (Keith) [William Keith's sister]
  - 3 letters, 1904 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 6)
- Chamberlin, Fred C.
  - Letter, Oct. 25, 1904, to Charles Fremont Pond. Requesting the use of Pond's negatives of the Midway Islands for a magazine article. (Carton 6)
- Clement, Henry Newell, 1841-
  - Letter, May 30, 1882, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 6)
- Cleveland, Theodore Keirstead
  - 8 letters, 1946-1954, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Written while President, Keith Art Association. (Carton 5)
  - Letter, May 18, 1954, to Brother Cornelius. Written while President, Keith Art Association. (Carton 9)
- Cline, Isaac Monroe
  - 3 letters (copies), 1937-1938 and n.d., to Brother Cornelius. Letter, n.d., is an extract. (Carton 9)
- Club Women's Franchise League of California
  - 11 letters, 1911-1924, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Some letters written to Jennie V. McBean. (Box 6)
- Coast, Oscar R.
  - 2 letters, 1910, to William Keith. Letter, Mar. 12, is incomplete. (Box 2)
  - Letter, Apr. 19, 1911, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Letter of condolence following Keith's death. (Box 6)
- Coath, Annie L.
  - 53 letters, 1928-1954, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
- Colby, Rachel (Vrooman)
  - Letter, n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 6)
- Colby, William Edward, 1875-1964
  - 4 letters, 1911-1939, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Letter, Apr. 12, 1939, comments on the inadequate lighting and space for the Keith Exposition at the Golden Gate International Exposition. (Box 6)
  - Letter, Mar. 18, 1931, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
  - Letter, Oct. 29, 1945, to Keith Art Association. (Carton 9)
- College Equal Suffrage League
  - 3 letters, 1911, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written by C. A. Whitney. (Box 6)
- Committee For Alameda County (Calif.)
  - Letter, Dec. 9, 1940, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written by J. R. Knowland and others, soliciting financial support for the State Chamber of Commerce. (Box 6)
- Converse, Sidney (Metcalfe), 1804-
  - Letter, Dec. 7, 1841, to Asa Baldwin Metcalfe. (Box 18)
- Coolbrith, Ina Donna, 1842-1928
  - 4 letters, 1907-1910, to William Keith. With these: form letter from the Spinners, soliciting funds for the "Coolbrith Fund;" printed copies of two poems she wrote about Keith. (Box 2)
  - 5 letters, 1910-1911 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 6)
- Corcoran Gallery of Art, Washington, D.C.
  - 2 letters, 1906, to William Keith. Written by F. B. McGuire, Secretary and Director, asking Keith to send one of his paintings for exhibition of contemporary American oil paintings. (Box 2)
- Cornelius Fidelis, Brother, 1877-1962
  - 511 letters, 1929-1947, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Primarily concern his biography of William Keith. (Box 6 and 7)
  - 262 letters, 1931-1955 and n.d., to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
  - 3 letters, 1947-1953, to Keith Art Association. (Carton 9)
- Crocker, Charles M.
  - Letter, Sept. 2, 1910, to William Keith. (Box 2)
  - Letter, Apr. 13, 1911, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 7)
- Crocker, May Hall
  - 2 letters, 1907-1911, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 7)
- Crocker Art Gallery, Sacramento, Calif.
  - 2 letters, 1946-1947, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written by F. P. Vickery, Director Manager. Letter, 1947, concerns their Keith exhibition. (Box 7)
  - 18 letters, 1946-1952, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Written mainly by F. P. Vickery and D. R. Birrell. Re Keith exhibition and permanent collection. (Carton 5)
  - Letter, Jan. 19, 1955, to Brother Cornelius. Written by Ernest Van Harlingen, Director. (Carton 9)
  - 3 letters, 1951-1954, to Keith Art Association. Written by D. R. Birrell and Ernest Van Harlingen. Letters, 1951-1952, are copies. (Carton 9)
- Cruess, William Vere, 1886-
  - Letter, n.d., to Keith Art Association. (Carton 9)
- Culbertson, Jack Arthur
  - 4 letters, 1954 and n.d., to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
  - 20 letters, 1952-1961 and n.d., to Inez (Henderson) Pond. (Carton 7)
- Culbertson, Mary Virginia (Pond) [Mrs. Jack Arthur Culbertson]
  - 5 letters, 1945-1947, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 7)
  - 33 letters, 1937-1955 and n.d., to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
  - 415 letters, 1941-1961 and n.d., to Inez (Henderson) Pond. (Carton 7)
  - 8 letters, 1941-1944, to Charles (McHenry) Pond. (Carton 8)
- Curtiss Flying Service
  - Letter, Nov. 1, 1929, to Charles McHenry Pond. (Carton 8)
- Daniels, Josephus, 1862-1948 See U.S. Secretary of the Navy
- Dargie, William Edward, 1854-1911
  - Letter, Oct. 24, 1876, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. Informing her that her poem was published in the Oakland Tribune and soliciting further contributions. (Box 15)
- Davidson, Ellinor Campbell
  - 15 letters, 1924-1942 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Letters, 1933, are copies. (Box 8)
  - 3 letters, 1934-1942 and n.d., to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Letter, 1942, concerns Genthe's negatives of Keith. (Carton 5)
  - Letter, Nov. 19, 1942, to Brother Cornelius. Re Genthe's negatives of Keith. (Carton 9)
- Davidson, George, 1825-1911
  - 4 letters, 1889-1910, to William Keith. Letters, 1893, are letters of introduction written to others. (Box 2)
  - 2 letters, 1900-1911, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 8)
  - Letter, May 21, 1886, to Emmanuel Benjamin Lamare. Copy written to E. S. Holden, commenting on Lamare's ability as an instructor of French. (Box 19)
- Davis, Jefferson, 1808-1889
  - Letter (copy), Feb. 2, 1889, to Mary Graham. In Miscellaneous Correspondence (Carton 9)
- Davis, Varina (Howell), 1826-1906 [Mrs. Jefferson Davis]
  - Letter, Feb. 28, 1902, to Emily Parsons Babcock Hay. (Box 21)
  - Letter (copy), Nov. 12, 1866, to Mary Graham. In Miscellaneous correspondence (Carton 9)
- Day, Clinton, 1847-1916
  - 2 letters, 1895 n.d., to William Keith. (Box 2)
- Dean, Caroline Lawrence See National American Suffrage Association
- Del Monte (Calif.) Art Gallery
  - Letter, Mar. 18, 1909, to William Keith. Written by A. F. Lafler, Curator. Re sale of several of Keith's paintings. (Box 2)
  - 4 letters, 1913-1934, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written by J. M. Blanch. Re sale of Keith paintings. (Box 8)
- Deutsch, Monroe Emanuel, 1879-1955 See Bancroft Library California. University. President
- Dickson, Edward Augustus, 1879-1956
  - Letter, Mar. 24, 1931, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Re possibility of a Keith exhibition. (Box 8)
  - Letter, Sept. 20, 1938, to Brother Cornelius. Typed copy. Re possibility of a Keith exhibition. (Carton 9)
- Drury, Aubrey, 1891- See Save-the-Redwoods League
- Drury, Wells, 1851-1932 See Berkeley, Calif. Chamber of Commerce
- Duniway, Abigail Scott See National Council of Women Voters
- Durant, Henry
  - Letter, Oct. 24, 1855, to John McHenry. Copy. Invitation to attend public exercises of The College of California. (Box 14)
- Duthie, Helena Charlotte, d. 1949 [William Keith's cousin]
  - 6 letters, 1910-1931, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Letters, 1928, contain information about Keith's family. Letters, 1928-1931, are copies. (Box 8)
- Easton, Giles A.
  - 2 letters, 1881, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. Thanking her for sending a copy of her book. (Box 15)
- Eastwood, Alice, 1859-1953
  - Letter, Dec. 13, 1938, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 8)
- Edwards, George Cunningham, 1852-
  - Letter, May 3, 1921, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Re the University of California. Class of 1879 reunion dinner. (Box 8)
- Elder, Paul, 1872- See Elder (Paul) and Company
- Elder (Paul) and Company
  - 2 letters, 1942, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written by Paul Elder. (Box 8)
- Eldridge, Chauncey F.
  - Letter, Feb. 18, 1926, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. With this: stock certificate for the Rocky Point Mining Company, Dec. 28, 1879, made out to William Keith. (Carton 5)
- Enquist, Mary Bisbee
  - 3 letters (copies), 1931-1941, to Brother Cornelius. (Carton 9)
- Fairbanks, Mary Jane (Mason), 1827-
  - 2 letters, 1851-1868, to Barbara Allen (Harris) Metcalfe. (Box 18)
- Fiske, George
  - Postcard to William Keith [Mar.29, 1909].
- Fiske, Turbes (Lummis)
  - Letter, n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 8)
- Foltz, Clara (Shortridge), 1849-1934
  - Letter, June 1, 1882, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 8)
- Genthe, Arnold, 1869-1942
  - 2 letters, 1937, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. With these: 2 letters, 1942, written by the executor of his estate, re negatives of William Keith. One letter, 1942, written to E. C. Davidson. (Box 8)
- Gibbon, Thomas Edward, 1860-1921
  - 2 letters, 1906, to William Keith. Requesting him to paint two pictures to replace his two which were lost in the earthquake and fire. (Box 2)
- Gillis, Mabel Ray, 1882-1961 See California. State Library, Sacramento
- Goddefroy, Anne Caroline (Marchand), d. 1873
  - 20 letters, 1850-1873, to Caroline (Goddefroy) Lamare. Letters, 1852, are fragments. (Box 20)
- Goode, George Brown, 1851-1896 See Smithsonian Institution
- Gordon, Kate M. See National American Suffrage Association
- Grant, Joseph Donohoe, 1858- See Save-the-Redwoods League
- Green, Charles Ernest, 1855-
  - 4 letters, 1904-1910, to William Keith. (Box 2)
  - 2 letters, 1911-1924, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 8)
- Greene, Edward Lee, 1843-1915 See California. University. College of Agriculture